Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions, 1870-1963 (MS Am 1804): Guide.
Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions,
1870-1963.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1804
Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964.
32 boxes (16 linear ft.)
Contains correspondence and writings of classics professor and Amherst College president Arthur Stanley Pease.
67M-159. Gift of Arthur Stanley Pease; received: 1964.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Arthur Stanley Pease (1881-1964) was a classics professor at the University of Illinois, Amherst, and Harvard. From 1927 to 1932 he was president of Amherst College. He was also an amateur botanist.
Organized into the following series:
I. Letters to Arthur Stanley Pease
II. Letters from Arthur Stanley Pease.
III. Other letters
IV. Compositions
Chiefly letters to Pease from many correspondents together with some drafts and carbon copies of outgoing letters, some family correspondence, and letters of others, and miscellaneous writings by Pease and others. Correspondence reflects Pease's research interests in the classics, professional activities (including the American Philological Association), and botanical interests.
- I. Letters to Arthur Stanley Pease
  Letters from various correspondents to Arthur Stanley Pease.
  - Abbott, Florence P. 1 letter; [1949], (1)
  - Abbott, Helen Oldfather. 1 letter; 1945., (2)
  - Abbott, Lawrence Fraser, 1859-1933. 1 letter; 1931., (3)
  - Academic press. 4 letters; 1962-1963. Also addressed to Richard Evans Schultes., (4)
  - Addison, James Thayer, 1887-1953. 1 letter; 1938., (5)
  - Agard, Walter Raymond, 1894- 1 letter; 1947., (6)
  - Agnew, Malcolm E. 1 letter; 1939., (7)
  - Alderman, William E. 1 letter; 1938., (8)
  - Aldrich, William T. 1 letter; 1937., (9)
  - Alexander, James W. 1 letter; 1947., (10)
  - Alexander, Paul Julius, 1910- 1 letter; 1940., (11)
  - Alexander, William Hardy, 1878- 4 letters; 1945-1951. No. 2 with a note by Arthur Stanley Pease., (12)
  - Allen, Bernard Meredith, 1864- 1 letter; 1942., (13)
  - Allen, Charles Herbert, 1848-1934. 2 letters; 1931., (14)
  - Allen, Hildegarde C. 1 letter; 1952., (15)
  - Allen, Walter. 5 letters; 1946-1948., (16)
  - Ames, Frederick S. 1 letter; [n.d.], (17)
  - Ames, Sir Herbert Brown, 1863- 2 letters; 1928., (18)
  - Amherst college. 1 letter; 1928., (19)
  - Anderson, C.J. 4 letters; 1938-1939 and [n.d.], (20)
  - Anderson, Warren DeWitt. 3 letters; 1950., (21)
  - Angell, James A. 3 letters; 1928-1929., (22)
  - Atkinson, Geoffroy, 1892-1960. 1 letter; 1933., (23)
  - The Atlantic monthly. 3 letters; 1912-1914., (24)
  - Atwood, Wallace Walter, 1872-1949. 2 letters; 1929-1931., (25)
  - Auslander, Joseph, 1897- 2 letters; 1942., (26)
  - Avery, Maurice Wescott. 1 letter; 1934., (27)
  - Ax, Johannes. 1 letter; 1956., (28)
  - Babbitt, Frank Cole, 1867- 4 letters; 1934., (29)
  - Babbott, Frank Lusk. 3 letters; 1931-1932., (30)
  - Baboock, Alfred Robert. 1 letter; 1953., (31)
  - Bacon, Benjamin Wesner, 1860-1932. 1 letter; 1907., (32)
  - Badger, Richard G. 1 letter; 1918., (33)
  - Bailey, Cyril, 1871-1957. 2 letters; 1935., (34)
  - Baird, Theodore, 1901- 11 letters; 1930-1961., (35)
  - Baker, James C. 1 letter; [n.d.], (36)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946. 1 letter; 1927., (37)
  - Baker, William. 1 letter; 1908., (38)
  - Baldwin, Charles Hart. 1 letter; 1930., (39)
  - Ball, Allen P. 7 letters; 1932-1933., (40)
  - Banta (George) Publishing Company, Menasha, Wis. 1 letter; 1921., (41)
  - Barlow, Claude W. 5 letters; 1933-1959., (42)
  - Barnes, Lincoln W. 1 letter; 1936., (43)
  - Barret, LeRoy Carr, 1877- 1 letter; 1935., (44)
  - Barstow, Robbins Wolcott. 1 letter; 1932. Addressed to Esther Stocks, secretary to Arthur Stanley Pease., (45)
  - Barton, Bruce, 1886- 1 letter; 1932., (46)
  - Barton, H.J. 3 letters; 1916-1929., (47)
  - Bartow, Howard Key. 2 letters; 1944., (48)
  - Bass, Perkins. 1 letter; 1961., (49)
  - Bassett, Edward Lewis, 1914- 19 letters; [1935]-1955 and [n.d.], (50)
  - Bassett, Henry Jewell. 2 letters; 1945., (51)
  - Bassett, Samuel Eliot, d. 1936. 12 letters; 1933-1935., (52)
  - Bate, Walter Jackson, 1918- 2 letters; 1958., (53)
  - Bates, J.M. 1 letter; 1927., (54)
  - Bates, Miner Lee. 1 letter; 1929., (55)
  - Baxter, Arthur Henry, 1871- 3 letters; 1938-1946., (56)
  - Bayley, John. 1 letter; 1954., (57)
  - Beach, Ella. 1 letter; 1963., (58)
  - Beach, Goodwin B. 2 letters; 1937-1953., (59)
  - Bean, Ralph C. 4 letters; 1952-1960., (60)
  - Beardslee, John Walter, 1914- 1 letter; 1948., (61)
  - Beekman, Frederick Warren. 1 letter; 1927., (62)
  - Beeson, Charles Henry, 1870- 2 letters; 1934-1936., (63)
  - Belding, Anson Wood. 1 letter; 1927., (64)
  - Bell, Bernard Iddings, 1886- 1 letter; 1927., (65)
  - Bell, Harold Idris, 1879- 1 letter; 1941., (66)
  - Benedict, Coleman Hamilton, 1911- 1 letter; 1958., (67)
  - Benner, Allen Rogers. 13 Letters; 1919-1940., (68)
  - Bennett, Charles Earnest. 2 letters; 1924-1927., (69)
  - Bennett, Curtis. 1 letter; [n.d.], (70)
  - Benton, F.M. 1 letter; 1938., (71)
  - Beston, Henry, 1888- 7 letters; 1952-1958 and [n.d.], (72)
  - Bewer, Julius August, 1877-1953. 1 letter; 1908., (73)
  - Bianchi, Martha Gilbert (Dickinson) 4 letters; 1930-1942 and [n.d.], (74)
  - Bidez, Joseph, 1867- 2 letters; 1935-1936. No.1 also signed by A. Delatte, J. Hubaux and H. van de Weerd. No.2 mimeographed., (75)
  - Bill, Clarence Powers. 7 letters; 1919-1934., (76)
  - Birkhoff, George David, 1884-1944. 3 letters; 1935., (77)
  - Bixler, Julius Seelye, 1894- 5 letters; 1942-1955., (78)
  - Blachly, Lou. 1 letter; 1959., (79)
  - Blaiklock, Edward Musgrave, 1903- 1 letter; [1957], (80)
  - Blake, Robert Pierpont, 1886-1950. 1 letter; 1941. Also signed by Robert Schlaifer,; Mason Hammond,; Sterling Dow., (81)
  - Blakeney, Edward Henry, 1869- 4 letters; [1930] and [n.d.], (82)
  - Bliss, Lawrence C. 1 letter; 1960., (83)
  - Bloch, Herbert, 1911- 28 letters; 1941-1959 and [n.d.], (84)
  - Blodgett, Frank D. 1 letter; 1928., (85)
  - Boas, Franz, 1858-1942. 2 letters; 1926., (86)
  - Bobrovnikoff, N.T. 1 letter; 1942., (87)
  - Bode, Boyd Henry, 1873-1953. 1 letter; 1941., (88)
  - Bolaffio, Robert E. 1 letter; 1958., (89)
  - Bonner, Campbell, 1876- 12 letters; 1916-1948., (90)
  - Booth, Evangeline, 1865- 1 letter, 1932., (91)
  - Borden, Elizabeth B. 2 letters; 1951-1952., (92)
  - Borrenpohl, Virginia. 1 letter; 1939., (93)
  - Bowan, Isaiah, 1878-1950. 2 letters; 1941 and [n.d.], (94)
  - Bowra, Sir Cecil Maurice, 1898- 2 letters; [1948] and [n.d.], (95)
  - Boyden, Frank L. 5 letters; 1927-1943. Nos.4 and 5 signed by secretary., (96)
  - Boynton, Morrison Russell. 1 letter; 1951., (97)
  - Brackett, Haven Darling. 11 letters; 1928-1951. No.5 with a note from Arthur Stanley Pease to James B. Munn, and with Munn's reply., (98)
  - Breasted, James Henry, 1865-1935. 1 letter; 1921., (99)
  - Bridges, Henry Styles, 1898-1961. 3 letters; 1954-1961., (100)
  - Brill, EJ., publishers. 1 letter; 1958., (101)
  - Brinton, Crane, 1898- 1 letter; 1946., (102)
  - Britt, Matthew, 1872- 1 letter; 1940., (103)
  - Brook, John. 1 letter; [n.d.], (104)
  - Brooks, John Pascal, 1861- 1 letter; 1932., (105)
  - Brooks, Robert Angus. 2 letters; 1944 and [n.d.], (106)
  - Broughton, Thomas Robert Shannon, 1900- 11 letters; 1942-1959 and [n.d.], (107)
  - Brouzas, Christopher George. 5 letters; 1925-1949., (108)
  - Brower, Reuben Arthur, 1908- 4 letters; 1930-1953., (109)
  - Brown, George. 2 letters; 1929-1930., (110)
  - Brownson, Carleton Lewis, 1866- 2 letters; 1936., (111)
  - Bruce, Henry Addington Bayley, 1874- 1 letter; 1941., (112)
  - Bruère, Richard Treat. 5 letters; 1950-1954 and [n.d.], (113)
  - Bryan, William Lowe, 1860- 1 letter; 1936., (114)
  - Buchanan, Milton Alexander, 1878- 1 letter; 1911., (115)
  - Buck, Carl Darling, 1866- 1 letter; 1921., (116)
  - Buck, Charles Henry, 1915- 1 letter; 1953., (117)
  - Buck Paul Herman, 1899- 5 letters; 1943-1946., (118)
  - Burch, George Bosworth, 1902- 1 letter; [1941], (119)
  - Burrell, Percy Jewett, 1877- 1 letter; 1946., (120)
  - Burrows, Reynold L. 1 letter; 1958., (121)
  - Buscardi, Corso. 6 letters; 1931-1936., (122)
  - Bush, Douglas, 1896- 6 letters; 1944-1959 and [n.d.], (123)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947. 1 letter; 1929., (124)
  - Butler, Pierce, 1886-1953. 1 letter; 1931., (125)
  - Butler, Thomas Crosby. 1 letter; [n.d.], (126)
  - Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957. 2 letters; 1931-1933., (127)
  - Cabrera, Francisco J. 1 letter; 1942. With the poem "Ad universitatem Nostrae Dominae"., (128)
  - Cadbury, Henry Joel, 1883- 3 letters; 1938-[1954], (129)
  - Cadman, Samuel Parkes, 1864-1936. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (130)
  - Calder, William Musgrave, 1932- 11 letter; 1954., (131)
  - Caldwell, Wallace Everett, 1890-1961. 1 letter; 1950., (132)
  - Calhoun, George Miller, 1886-1942. 37 letters; 1933-1942 and [n.d.] Nos.13 and 25 with a note by Arthur Stanley Pease. No. 21 with excerpts from letters of E.K. Rand and W.A. Oldfather. No. 24 see also Waldo G. Leland to George Calhoun, no. 1082., (133)
  - Callahan, John Francis, 1912- 2 letters; 1949-1951., (134)
  - Cameron, Donald. 1 letter; [n.d.], (135)
  - Campbell, Peter, G.R. 1 letter; 1939., (136)
  - Campbell, Vera. 2 letters; 1962 and [n.d.], (137)
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford, 1871-1945. 1 letter; 1938. By secretary., (138)
  - Canter, Howard Vernon, 1873- 11 letters; 1918-1941., (139)
  - Caplan, Harry, 1896- 5 letters; 1937-1955., (140)
  - Capps, Edward, 1866- 10 letters; 1920-1948 and [n.d.] No.6 signed by secretary., (141)
  - Carey, Frederick Mason. 2 letters; 1946-1952., (142)
  - Carpenter, Charles Carroll, 1836-1918. 1 letter; 1911., (143)
  - Carr, Wilbert Lester, 1875- 11 letter; 1933., (144)
  - Carpenter, Elsie. 1 letter; 1963., (145)
  - Carroll, John Patrick. 3 letters; [1944-1946] and [n.d.], (146)
  - Carroll, Mitchell, 1870-1925. 1 letter; 1912., (147)
  - Cartollo, Ercole, 1889-1946. 2 letters; 1932., (148)
  - Carver, Thomas Nixon, 1865- 1 letter; 1930., (149)
  - Cary, Earnest. 4 letters; [1938]-1942 and [n.d.], (150)
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944. 1 letter; 1927., (151)
  - Chafee, Zechariah, 1885-1957. 18 letters; 1932-1954 and [n.d.], (152)
  - Chamberlin, Henry Harmon, 1873- 3 letters; 1942., (153)
  - Chambers, Mortimer Hardin, 1927- 6 letters; 1953-1956 and [n.d.], (154)
  - Chapin, John S. 1 letter; 1935., (155)
  - Charlesworth, Martin Percival, 1895-1950. 2 letters; 1923-1936., (156)
  - Chase, Alston Hurd, 1906- 5 letters; 1936-1954., (157)
  - Chase, George Henry, 1874-1952. 7 letters; 1922-1943., (158)
  - Chase, Harry Woodburn, 1883-1955. 1 letter; 1931., (159)
  - Cherniss, Harold Fredrik, 1904- 6 letters; 1935-1946., (160)
  - Chickering, Edward Conner, 1875- 2 letters; 1920., (161)
  - Chipman, Miner. 2 letters; 1913., (162)
  - Christopher, Joseph Patrick, 1890- 54 letters; 1920-1956., (163)
  - Chute, Richard. 1 letter; 1954., (164)
  - Clark, Albert Curtis, 1859-1937. 2 letters; 1923-1924., (165)
  - Clark, DeWitt. 1 telegram; 1927., (166)
  - Clark, Walter Eugene, 1881-1960. 6 letters; 1936-1945. No.4 by secretary., (167)
  - Clarke, Charles H. 1 letter; 1932., (168)
  - Clausen, Wendell Vernon, 1923- 4 letters; 1950-1956 and [n.d.], (169)
  - Cleasby, Harold Loomis, 1876- 1 letter; 1919., (170)
  - Clough, Benjamin Crocker, 1888- 4 letters; 1931-1941., (171)
  - Coburn, Aaron C. 1 letter; 1929., (172)
  - Coffin; Ernest A. 1 letter; 1943., (173)
  - Coffin, Harrison Cadwallader. 1 letter; 1959., (174)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1877-1954. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (175)
  - Cole, Charles Woolsey, 1906- 3 letters; 1947-1952., (176)
  - Cole, Samuel Valentine, 1851-1925. 1 letter; 1923., (177)
  - Coleman, Norman Frank, 1874- 1 letter; 1932., (178)
  - Colker, Marvin Leonard. 9 letters; 1950-1953 and [n.d.], (179)
  - Comfort, William Wistar, 1874- 3 letters; 1931-1946., (180)
  - Compton, Karl Taylor, 1887-1954. 1 letter; 1934., (181)
  - Comstock, Ada Louise, 1876- 15 letters; 1930-1942 and [n.d.], (182)
  - Conant, James Bryant, 1893- 13 letters; 1934-1944., (183)
  - Conklin, Frank B. 1 letter; [1961], (184)
  - Constable, Giles. 3 letters; [1950]-1962 and [n.d.], (185)
  - Constable, William George, 1887- 5 letter; 1943-1948., (186)
  - Cook, E.B. 1 letter; 1908., (187)
  - Cooley, George R. 44 letters; [1950]-1962 and [n.d.], (188)
  - Cooley, Myra. 9 letters; 1958-1962., (189)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, pres. U.S., 1872-1933. 5 letters; 1930-1932., (190)
  - Coolidge, Grace (Goodhue) 1879-1957. 1 letter; 1928., (191)
  - Coolidge, Julian Lowell, 1873-1954. 1 letter; [n.d.], (192)
  - Coolidge, Marcus Allen, 1865-1947. 1 letter; 1932., (193)
  - Cortwright, E. Everett. 1 letter; 1931., (194)
  - Cotton, Norris. 2 letters; 1954-1961., (195)
  - Cottrell, George William, Jr. 3 letters; 1958-1959., (196)
  - Couch, Herbert Newell, 1899- 3 letters; 1945-1946., (197)
  - Coulter, Cornelia Catlin, 1885- 12 letters; 1942-1955., (198)
  - Coulter, Francis C. 1 letter; 1957., (199)
  - Cousins, John A. 2 letters; 1930, (200)
  - Cowles, Martha. 1 letter; 1959., (201)
  - Cowlie, William L. 2 letters; 1913., (202)
  - Cowling, Donald John, 1880- 3 letters; 1931., (203)
  - Cox, Cartier. 1 letter; 1944., (204)
  - Cox, Channing Harris, 1879- 2 letters; 1929-1930., (205)
  - Crawford, Frederick Stuart, Jr. 7 letters; 1938-1959., (206)
  - Cronkhite, Bernice Brown. 1 letter; 1936., (207)
  - Crosby, Henry Lamar, 1880- 7 letters; 1908-1945., (208)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius, 1862-1948. 2 letters; 1931., (209)
  - Cummin, John W. 2 letters; 1942 and [n.d.], (210)
  - Cunningham, Harrison E. 8 letters; 1915-1943., (211)
  - Curley, James Michael, 1874- 1 letter; 1931., (212)
  - Curtis, Charles Pelham, 1891- 2 letters; 1944 and [n.d.], (213)
  - Curtis, Richard Cary. 1 letter; 1947., (214)
  - Cutler, Henry Franklin, 1862-1945. 1 letter; 1931., (215)
  - Cutter, R. Ammi. 4 letters; 1944-1958., (216)
  - Dabney, Vaughan. 18 letters; 1932-1953., (217)
  - Dame, Alfred M. 1 letter; 1959., (218)
  - Davies, Arthur, H. 1 letter; 1933., (219)
  - Davies, Thurston. 1 letter; 1946., (220)
  - Davis, Alan L. 2 letters; 1959-1960., (221)
  - Davis, Harold S. 1 letter; 1944., (222)
  - Dennett, Tyler, 1883-1949. 1 letter; 1936., (223)
  - Derry, Cecil Thayer. 2 letters; 1959-1961., (224)
  - Dewey, Harry P. 3 letters; 1932-1951., (225)
  - Dewey, Melvil, 1851-1931. 2 letters; 1927., (226)
  - De Witt, Norman Wentworth, 1876- 2 letters; 1935-1946., (227)
  - Dow, Agnes. 2 letters; 1943., (228)
  - Dow, Sterling, 1903- 2 letters; 1951 and [n.d.], (229)
  - Downey, F.X. 1 letter; 1927, (230)
  - Eades, Elizabeth. 1 letter; 1958, (231)
  - Eames, Edward W. 2 letters; 1930-1932., (232)
  - Eaton, Edward Dwight, 1851- 1 letter; 1913., (233)
  - Eaton, George J. 1 letter; 1920., (234)
  - Eaton, Richard J. 30 letters; 1959-1962 and [n.d.], (235)
  - Eaton, Thaxter. 1 letter; 1953., (236)
  - Edmonds, Walter Dumaux, 1903- 4 letters; 1944-1952., (237)
  - Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926. 1 letter; 1908., (238)
  - Eliot, Samuel Atkins, 1862-1950. 1 letter; 1928., (239)
  - Eliot, Thomas Hopkinson, 1907- 3 letters; 1941., (240)
  - Else, Gerald Frank, 1908- 1 letter; 1961., (241)
  - Emerson, Mary H.A. 1 letter; 1952., (242)
  - Emerton, Ephraim, 1851-1935. 1 letter; 1927., (243)
  - Epinosa, Polit, Aurelio. 1 letter; 1935., (244)
  - Estes, Thomas C. 4 letters; 1930., (245)
  - Esty, Edward T. 1 letter; 1927., (246)
  - Evans, Daniel, 1866-1943. 2 letters; 1927-1941., (247)
  - Evans, Elizabeth Cornelia, 1905- 2 letters; 1959., (248)
  - Ewin, Lucy H. 1 letter; 1932., (249)
  - Eyde, Richard Husted. 4 letters; 1959., (250)
  - Fairclough, Henry Rushton, 1862-1938. 1 letter; 1935., (251)
  - Faunce, William Herbert Perry, 1859-1930. 1 letter; 1928, (252)
  - Feldman, Louis Harry. 2 letters; 1958-1962., (253)
  - Fernald, Merritt Lyndon, 1873- 1 letter; 1949, (254)
  - Ferris, Lincoln. 4 letters; 1959 and [n.d.], (255)
  - Ferry, Frederick Carlos, 1868- 1 letter; 1929., (256)
  - Field, Fred T. 2 letters; 1931., (257)
  - Finley, John Huston, 1863-1940. 4 letters; 1927-1928., (258)
  - Finley, John Huston, 1904- 1 letter; [n.d.], (259)
  - Fisher, William. 2 letters; 1928 and [n.d.] See also no.(805)., (260)
  - Fiske, Henry M. 1 letter; 1946., (261)
  - Flickinger, Roy Caston, 1876-1942. 10 letters; 1932-1935. No.3; see also George A. Plimpton to Roy C. Flickinger (10 Nov 1932) no.1116. Concerning the American Philogical Association., (262)
  - No entry., (263)
  - Fobes, Francis Howard, d. 1957. 1 letter; 1935., (264)
  - Folger, Emily (Jordan) 1 letter; 1932., (265)
  - Forbes, Charles Henry, 1866- 1 letter; 1932., (266)
  - Forbes, Stephen Alfred, 1844-1930. 1 letter; 1924., (267)
  - Fox, William Sherwood, 1878- 9 letters; 1958-1962., (268)
  - Fraenkel, Edward, 1888- 1 letter; 1959., (269)
  - Frank, Tenney, 1876-1939. 10 letters; 1933-1935 and [n.d.], (270)
  - Franklin, Lucy Jenkins. 1 letter; 1927., (271)
  - Frost, Robert, 1875-1963. 2 letters; 1928-1929., (272)
  - Frost, Sarah L. 1 letter; 1935, (273)
  - Frueh, Nancy Torrey. 1 letter; 1953., (274)
  - Fuess, Claude Moore, 1885-1963. 10 letters; 1931-1935., (275)
  - Fuller, Ernest S. 1 letter; 1934., (276)
  - Funaioli, Gino, 1878- 1 letter; 1958. Facsimile signature., (277)
  - Galbraith, A.V. 1 letter; 1932., (278)
  - Galbraith, John S. 5 letters; 1929-1935., (279)
  - Ganss, George E. 1 letter; 1947., (280)
  - Gardiner, Tudor. 1 letter; [n.d.], (281)
  - Gardner, Edith Jordan. 1 letter; 1952., (282)
  - Garfield, Harry Augustus, 1863-1942. 5 letters; 1930-1931., (283)
  - Gasquet, J.A. 1 letter; 1912., (284)
  - Gates, Milo H. 4 letters; 1927-1930., (285)
  - Gatti, Giuseppe. 1 letter; 1908., (286)
  - Gay, Edwin Francis, 1867-1946. 2 letters; 1934-1936., (287)
  - Geer, Russell Mortimer. 5 letters; 1929-1941., (288)
  - Gelsomino, Remo. 1 letter; 1959., (289)
  - General Motors corporation. 1 letter; 1947., (290)
  - Gettell, Richard Glenn. 1 letter; 1957., (291)
  - Getty, Margaret. 9 letters; 1950-1955., (292)
  - Getty, Robert John. 3 letters; 1936-1951., (293)
  - [Gilbert], Theodore. 1 letter; 1932., (294)
  - [Gilbert] Walter. 1 letter; 1934., (295)
  - Gillett, Frederick Huntington, 1851- 3 letters; 1930-1931., (296)
  - Gillingham, Allan George. 3 letters; 1945-1952., (297)
  - Gilmore, Myron Piper, 1910- 1 letter; 1959., (298)
  - Gleason, Clarence Willard, 1866-1942. 3 letters; [n.d.], (299)
  - Gleason, Henry Allan, 1882- 7 letters; 1959-1961 and [n.d.], (300)
  - Gleason, Herbert Wendell, 1855- 1 letter; 1927., (301)
  - Goodspeed, Edgar Johnson, 1871-1950. 1 letter; 1938., (302)
  - Grandgent, Charles Hall, 1862-1939. 2 letters; 1902-1921., (303)
  - Grant, Frederick Clifton, 1891- 5 letters; 1945-1948., (304)
  - Grant, John. 3 letters; 1947 and [n.d.], (305)
  - Grant, Robert, 1877- 7 letters; 1949-1953., (306)
  - Grant, William Leonard. 1 letter; 1945., (307)
  - Graustein, Jeannette Elizabeth, 1916- 1 letter; 1961., (308)
  - Gray, Clifton Daggett, 1874- 3 letters; 1938-1941., (309)
  - Green, Robert M. 5 letters; 1938-1948., (310)
  - Greene, Evarts Boutell, 1870-1947. 5 letters; 1921-1944., (311)
  - Greene, Herbert Eveleth. 1 letter; 1908., (312)
  - Greene, Jerome Davis, 1874- 1 letter; 1938., (313)
  - Greene, William Chase, 1890- 33 letters; 1928-1962 and [n.d.], (314)
  - Greenlee, Jacob Harold, 1918- 1 letter; 1947., (315)
  - Greenough, Chester Noyes, 1874-1938. 3 letters; 1934-1938., (316)
  - Greindl, Max, 1913- 2 letters; 1940., (317)
  - Grenfell, Sir Wilfred Thomason, 1865-1940. 2 letters; 1931., (318)
  - Griffin, Nathaniel Edward, 1873- 1 letter; 1936., (319)
  - Grimm, Ludwig. 2 letters; 1910., (320)
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875- 3 letters; 1927-1942., (321)
  - Grynpas, Benedykt. 2 letters; 1947., (322)
  - Gudeman, Alfred, 1862- 1 letter; 1922., (323)
  - Guernsey, Roscoe. 1 letter; 1933., (324)
  - Guglielmo, Francesco, 1872- 1 letter; 1934., (325)
  - Guinagh, Kevin, 1897- 3 letters; 1936-1939., (326)
  - Gulick, Charles Burton, 1868- 18 letters; 1932-1949 and [n.d.], (327)
  - Gulick, Charles B., Jr. 1 letter; [1962], (328)
  - Gulick, Gertrude S. 1 letter; 1961., (329)
  - Gummere, B. 1 letter; [n.d.], (330)
  - Gummere, Richard Mott, 1883- 38 letters; 1920-1961., (331)
  - Guthrie, William Keith Chambers, 1906- 1 letter; 1941., (332)
  - Gutwirth, Marc Raphael. 2 letters; [n.d.], (333)
  - Haarhoff, Theodore Johannes, 1892- 1 letter; 1944., (334)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue, 1875- 14 letters; 1925-1945. No.4 also addressed to E.K. Rand., (335)
  - Hageman, Howard Garberich. 1 letter; 1942., (336)
  - Hagen, Benno von, 1883- 1 letter; 1910., (337)
  - Hahn, E. Adelaide, 1893- 1 letter; 1944., (338)
  - Haight, Elizabeth Hazelton, 1872- 4 letters; 1946-1955., (339)
  - Haley, Sadie. 5 letters; 1954-1962., (340)
  - Hall, Norman A. 1 letter; 1954., (341)
  - Halliday, William Reginald, 1886- 7 letters; 1924-1928., (342)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- 40 letters; 1937-1961 and [n.d.], (343)
  - Hanfmann, George Maxim Anossov, 1911- 16 letters; 1935-1955., (344)
  - Hanford, Alfred Chester, 1891- 3 letters; 1935-1937., (345)
  - Harding, C.R. 1 letter; 1921, Mimeographed., (346)
  - Haring, Clarence Henry, 1885-1960. 3 letters; 1944-1948., (347)
  - Harman, Marian, 1899- 1 letter; 1929., (348)
  - Harmon, Austin M. 6 letters; 1938-1945. See also Martha (Harmon) Porter to Arthur Stanley Pease, no.(672). No.5 with a copy of a letter from Stanley B. Smith to A.M. Harmon., (349)
  - Harringoon, Karl Pomeroy, 1861-1953. 8 letters; 1921-1947., (350)
  - Harrop, Arthur Henry. 1 letter; 1938., (351)
  - Harry, Joseph Edward, 1863- 1 letter; 1941., (352)
  - Harsh, Philip Whaley, 1905- 14 letters; 1938-1954., (353)
  - Harvard trust company, Cambridge, Mass. 1 letter; 1961., (354)
  - Harvard university press. 8 letters; 1934-1958., (355)
  - Hatch, Norman L. 1 letter; 1954., (356)
  - Hatch, Robert McConnell, bp., 1910- 6 letters; 1951-1959 and [n.d.], (357)
  - Hatch, William Henry Paine, 1875- 22 letters; 1910-1958 and [n.d.], (358)
  - Haufsleiter, J. 2 letters; 1937-1938., (359)
  - Havelock, Eric Alfred. 4 letters; 1918-1955., (360)
  - Hawthorne, John G. 1 letter; 1940., (361)
  - Hazelton, Roger, 1909- 1 letter; 1945., (362)
  - Heffner, Edward Hoch, 1886- 1 letter; 1945., (363)
  - Heidel, William Arthur, 1868-1941. 3 letters; 1921-1932., (364)
  - Heller, John Lewis. 16 letters; 1948-1958., (365)
  - Henderson, Gregory. 2 letters; 1946 and [n.d.], (366)
  - Hendrickson, George Lincoln, 1865- 26 letters; 1928-[1961] and [n.d.], (367)
  - Henrici, Max. 1 letter; 1953., (368)
  - Herescu, Niculae I. 3 letters; 1946-1947., (369)
  - Herrick, Asbury Haven. 2 letters; 1943., (370)
  - Herrick, Everett Carleton. 9 letters, 1932-1945., (371)
  - Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966. 4 letters; 1936-1952., (372)
  - Hewitt, Joseph William, 1875-1938. 56 letters; 1908-1935. Concerning the American Philological Association., (373)
  - Higginson, Ida (Agassiz) 1837-1950. 1 letter; 1900., (374)
  - Hincks, Carroll C. 2 letters; 1930-1931., (375)
  - Hincks, Edward Young, 1844- 6 letters; 1921-1924., (376)
  - Hinman, George Warren, 1869- 3 letters; 1928-1938., (377)
  - Hodgdon, Albion Reed. 2 letters; 1959., (378)
  - Hodgman, Arthur Winfred. 7 letters; 1921-1946., (379)
  - Hörle, Josef. 1 letter; 1936., (380)
  - Hoerner, Hadwig. 2 letters; 1958., (381)
  - Hofmann, J.B. 8 letters; 1923-1937., (382)
  - Holt, Hamilton, 1872-1951. 2 letters; 1933-1936. No.2 signed by secretary., (383)
  - Hoor, Marten???ten. 1 letter; 1937., (384)
  - Hooton, Earnest Albert, 1887-1954. 1 letter; 1938., (385)
  - Hopkins, Ernest Martin, 1877- 2 letters; 1927., (386)